<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reproducible Data Analysis</title>
    <link>/data_analysis_2020/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Reproducible Data Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/data_analysis_2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data frames: Your new favorite data structure</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/notes/data-frames/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/notes/data-frames/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Discusses the data structure called data frames: what they are and why they are so important.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 Resources</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/resources/week03-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/resources/week03-resources/</guid>
      <description>  The RStudio list of cheat sheets. The Data Import, Data Transformation, Data Visualization, and RStudio IDE cheat sheets will be particularly valuable to you. R for Data Science Chapter 3 Hadley Wickham on Tidy data. Note that this old-ish paper uses the syntax of a package called plyr, which is a bit different from the tidyverse counterpart called dplyr.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework 3</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/homework/hw03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/homework/hw03/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;This homework, as well as homework 2, is due Wednesday Sept 16. Lecture notes coming ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Style Guide</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/resources/style-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/resources/style-guide/</guid>
      <description>Style is substance Donald Knuth famously wrote “Instead of imagining that our main task is to instruct a computer what to do, let us concentrate rather on explaining to human beings what we want a computer to do.” (Knuth, 1983, Literate Programming).
Accordingly, it is important to write our code so that it is easily readable by humans. What defines easily readable? Well, it helps for the whole community of readers to be working from a common set of rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting help in R</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/notes/help/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/notes/help/</guid>
      <description>Help on specific functions Every function in R has a an associated documentaion file. In RStudio, typing the name of the function, prefaced by ?, will pull up the documentation for that function. For instance, try ?sum[On my machine, RStudio sometimes gets over-excited about auto-completing and tries to fill in the name of a longer function. Just type backspace when that happens.] (you don’t need the ()): in the lower-right-hand panel of RStudio you’ll see a documentation displayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to packages</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/notes/packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/notes/packages/</guid>
      <description>Like all programming languages, R relies on a base language, which is extended by packages. When you installed R, you only installed the base language1. However, base R can only do so much.
Most of R’s power lies is in its packages. Need to do timeseries forecasting? You’ll want the forecast package. Need to do multivariate statistics? vegan is world-leading. Currently there are more than 16,000 packages listed on CRAN for basically every task you can imagine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 resources</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/resources/week-2-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/resources/week-2-resources/</guid>
      <description>This week has a bunch of R basics. Chapters 1 and 4 of R for Data Science are a good place to start. However, I would like you all to practice your Git/Github skills by adding introductory references to this list.  To do that:
 Go to https://github.com/adsteen/490_site_source, which contains the source code for this website Press the “Fork” link to make a copy of that Git “repo” (repository) On your version of this repository on the GitHub website (it’ll be labeled your-user-name/490_site_source, navigate to contents/resources/2020-09-08-Week_02-resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework 2</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/homework/hw02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/homework/hw02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This homework, as well as homework 3, is due Wednesday Sept 16. Lecture notes coming ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to R via the tidyverse</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/notes/intro-to-r-via-the-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/notes/intro-to-r-via-the-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>Placeholder for Introduction to R via the Tidyverse lecture notes</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>