<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on Reproducible Data Analysis</title>
    <link>/data_analysis_2020/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on Reproducible Data Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/data_analysis_2020/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 Resources</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/resources/week03-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/resources/week03-resources/</guid>
      <description>  The RStudio list of cheat sheets. The Data Import, Data Transformation, Data Visualization, and RStudio IDE cheat sheets will be particularly valuable to you. R for Data Science Chapter 3 Hadley Wickham on Tidy data. Note that this old-ish paper uses the syntax of a package called plyr, which is a bit different from the tidyverse counterpart called dplyr.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Style Guide</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/resources/style-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/resources/style-guide/</guid>
      <description>Style is substance Donald Knuth famously wrote “Instead of imagining that our main task is to instruct a computer what to do, let us concentrate rather on explaining to human beings what we want a computer to do.” (Knuth, 1983, Literate Programming).
Accordingly, it is important to write our code so that it is easily readable by humans. What defines easily readable? Well, it helps for the whole community of readers to be working from a common set of rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 resources</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/resources/week-2-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/resources/week-2-resources/</guid>
      <description>This week has a bunch of R basics. Chapters 1 and 4 of R for Data Science are a good place to start. However, I would like you all to practice your Git/Github skills by adding introductory references to this list.  To do that:
 Go to https://github.com/adsteen/490_site_source, which contains the source code for this website Press the “Fork” link to make a copy of that Git “repo” (repository) On your version of this repository on the GitHub website (it’ll be labeled your-user-name/490_site_source, navigate to contents/resources/2020-09-08-Week_02-resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>