<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>week02 on Reproducible Data Analysis</title>
    <link>/data_analysis_2020/tags/week02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in week02 on Reproducible Data Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/data_analysis_2020/tags/week02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting help in R</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/notes/help/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/notes/help/</guid>
      <description>Help on specific functions Every function in R has a an associated documentaion file. In RStudio, typing the name of the function, prefaced by ?, will pull up the documentation for that function. For instance, try ?sum[On my machine, RStudio sometimes gets over-excited about auto-completing and tries to fill in the name of a longer function. Just type backspace when that happens.] (you don’t need the ()): in the lower-right-hand panel of RStudio you’ll see a documentation displayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to packages</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/notes/packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/notes/packages/</guid>
      <description>Like all programming languages, R relies on a base language, which is extended by packages. When you installed R, you only installed the base language1. However, base R can only do so much.
Most of R’s power lies is in its packages. Need to do timeseries forecasting? You’ll want the forecast package. Need to do multivariate statistics? vegan is world-leading. Currently there are more than 16,000 packages listed on CRAN for basically every task you can imagine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework 2</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/homework/hw02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/homework/hw02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This homework, as well as homework 3, is due Wednesday Sept 16. Lecture notes coming ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to R via the tidyverse</title>
      <link>/data_analysis_2020/notes/intro-to-r-via-the-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data_analysis_2020/notes/intro-to-r-via-the-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>Placeholder for Introduction to R via the Tidyverse lecture notes</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>